# **Charles X. Morrissey**

Senior Front-end Web Engineer

**t** (+1) 347 385 1985 **e** me@charles-x.com **w** work.charles-x.com

#### About

Senior Front-end Developer currently residing in Brooklyn, NY.

Background in illustration and design with over 15 years industry experience.

Focus on clean design and standards-based accessible web sites.

Consistently deliver high-quality services to clients and design agencies with a strong sense of ownership, urgency and attention to detail.

# Experience

Huge 2015-2020

Senior Web Engineer on United Airlines | 2019 - 2020

- Worked with a team of developers, designers and business analysts to build a tool to manage flight upgrades and integrate United Airlines' new PlusPoints system.
- Built reusable UI components with React, CSS modules and Storybook.
- Utilized React, Redux, Redux-Saga and ReSelect to handle complex business logic and asynchronous data/service integrations.
- Employed industry best practices, modularization, and linting to ensure maintainable quality codebases.
- Conducted code reviews to ensure standards and best practices.

# Senior Web Engineer on Value Retail | 2019

- Worked with a team of developers and designers to build a content managed website using Gatsby and Contentful for luxury shopping boutiques based in Europe and Asia.
- Built reusable UI components with React, Styled Components and Storybook.
- Created automation scripts to handle data migrations using the Contentful API.
- Conducted code reviews to ensure quality and best practices.
- Presented new features in weekly client demos.

# Front-end Lead on Revlon and Almay | 2018 - 2019

- Led the front-end team on the replatform and redesign of Revlon and Almay websites.
- Made front-end architectural decisions and worked closely with backend engineers to integrate into the Sitecore platform.

- Setup a complex build system with webpack to accommodate multiple sites themes, templates and components.
- Built reusable UI components with VueJS.
- Setup a local GraphQl server to mock data for rapid development.
- Conducted code reviews to ensure quality and best practices.
- Worked closely to integrate with third party vendors Shoppable and BazaarVoice.
- Front-end representation in sprint planning/forecasting and backlog grooming, client demos and client meetings.
- Worked closely with the analytics and SEO team to create several custom utilities to meet business requirements.
- Wrote technical memos and architectural design documents as client deliverables.

# Front-end Lead on Think with Google | 2017 - 2018

- Led the front-end team on the replatform and redesign of Think with Google.
- Made front-end architectural decisions and project setup using VueJs, VueX, PostCSS, Vanilla JS and webpack.
- Conducted code reviews to ensure quality and best practices.
- Mentored junior developers, giving feedback and providing guidance for technical and career growth.
- Integrated AMP, Google Optimize and several custom analylitics utilities.
- Contributed to the backend by creating Django field migrations and basic model updates.
- Wrote technical memos and architectural design documents as client deliverables.

# Senior Web Engineer on Think with Google Data Gallery | 2015 - 2017

- Developed a search app for Think with Google using Angular, Google Closure Compiler JS and Jinja templating
- Worked with several microservices, including writing a custom atomic design style library to be imported into each service.

### Firstborn

Senior Front-end Developer | 2015

Lead Developer on The Aspen Institute, Aquafina and Disney Dream Up.

#### Area 17

Senior Front-end Developer | 2014 - 2015

Front-end Developer on projects including Facebook - State of Connectivity, Red Bull Studios, and various internal websites.

# King & Partners

Technology Lead | 2012 - 2014

Technical direction, planning and management. Mentoring and hiring for the development team. Project scoping and estimates, proposal and technical writing. Hands on development for fashion, luxury brands and real estate industries.

### Sweden Unlimited

Senior Front-end Developer | 2004 - 2012

Lead Developer in charge of engineering and creating interactive accounts alongside the company's founding partner, design and production team.

Was in charge of translating the client's goal and Creative Director's vision while executing it with the industry innovative standards and details.

Such accounts varying from updates to e-commerce rebuilds include Alexander Wang, Grandlife Hotels, Diane von Furstenberg, Marc Jacobs, Nicole Miller, Proenza Schouler, Tess Giberson, Vera Wang, Visionaire...

### Will Work For Good

Freelance Web Developer | 2008 - 2011

Front and back-end development for New York based art and design studio. Created various works from television series, Tim and Eric to clients such as Doug Atkin, Sundance Channel, and Viva Radio.

# **American Apparel**

Freelance Web Developer | 2008 - 2009

Head of the front and back-end development of established fashion brand.

Also in charge of company's various projects including first in-house online radio station.

#### Skills

Javascript (ES6/7, Vue, VueX, React, Redux, Redux Sagas, Storybook, Google Closure Compiler, Webpack, Mocha, Jest), CSS, PostCSS, SASS, Django, Wordpress, CraftCMS, Expression Engine Python, PHP, MYSQL

### <u>Design</u>

Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, Invision, Zeplin

### **Education**

University of the Arts Illustration / Printmaking | Class of 1996